Guide to the Hal and Barbara Dodge Borland Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- I. 1965 and 1981 Acquisitions, 1921-1981; 36.42; (44 boxes)
  - Valor and Wapiti Pete, correspondence with Farrar & Rinehart, 1934-1943 (Box 15)
  - Wapiti Pete, correspondence, 1938-1939 (Box 15)
  - Beyond Your Doorstep, "Nature Handbook," notes and plans, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 15)
  - King of Squaw Mountain, typescript carbon, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Beyond Your Doorstep, scrapbook of comments and reviews, 1962 (Box 15)
  - America Is Americans, typescript and typescript carbon, correspondence, and clippings, 1942-1956; 3 (Box 15)
  - Poems, typescript, typescript carbon, and clippings, undated (Box 15)
  - "I am an American," typescript, typescript carbon, and clippings, 1942 (Box 15)
  - How to Write and Sell Non-Fiction, typescript and typescript carbon, circa 1955; 2 (Box 15)
  - How to Write and Sell Non-Fiction, comments and reviews, 1956 (Box 15)
  - How to Write and Sell Non-Fiction, correspondence, 1955 (Box 15)
  - "Front Porch in Manhattan," typescript carbon, 1946 (Box 15)
  - "Novelette Idea," typescript carbon, undated (Box 15)
  - New York Times, correspondence, 1937-1963 (Box 15)
  - "Whistle-Stop," typescript carbon and correspondence, 1951 (Box 15)
  - "Big Freight Rolling," typescript, typescript carbon, and correspondence, 1944 (Box 15)
  - "Lost Retreat," typescript carbon and clipping, 1951 (Box 15)
  - "Touring, Then and Now," typescript and typescript carbon, 1951 (Box 15)
  - Rocky Mountain Tipi Tales, typescript carbon, circa 1924 (Box 15)
  - Trouble Valley, correspondence and clippings, 1935 (Box 15)
  - "Borland - comments," correspondence and printed material, undated (Box 15)
  - Wing, Willis Kingsley, correspondence, 1958 (Box 15)
  - Pat, third typescript carbon, undated (Box 16)
  - Blessie, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 16)
  - Countryman: A Summary of Belief, typescript, undated (Box 16)
  - How to Write and Sell Non-Fiction, typescript, undated (Box 16)
  - Audubon magazines with Hal Borland articles, 1970 (Box 16)
  - Assorted magazines with Hal Borland articles, 1963-1970 (Box 16)
  - "Earth-kin," typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 16)
  - Rocky Mountain Tipi Tales, illustrations, 1923 (Box 16)
  - "'Dobe," typescript, 1924 (Box 16)
  - Early fiction, typescript and printed material, 1928 (Box 16)
  - "Time of Flight," typescript carbon, 1935 (Box 16)
  - "These Things Endure," typescript, circa 1951 (Box 16)
  - "Magazine & Newspaper Clippings," scrapbook, 1950s-1960s (Box 16)
  - Early stories, tear sheets, undated (Box 16)
  - An American Year, typescript, circa 1946 (Box 16)
  - An American Year, correspondence, 1946 (Box 16)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1934-1952 (Box 17)
  - Poems printed in The Turkey Quill, typescripts and manuscript notebook, 1920s (Box 17)
  - Homeland: A Report from the Country, typescript carbon, undated (Box 17)
  - An American Year, correspondence and notes, 1945-1946 (Box 17)
  - "Citations, etc.," correspondence and printed material, 1944-1959 (Box 17)
  - "Early Poetry," draft, holograph and printed versions, circa 1921 (Box 17)
  - "Old Farmers Almanac Poems," correspondence and typescripts, circa 1959-1961 (Box 17)
  - Progressive Magazine, correspondence and articles, 1957-1964 (Box 17)
  - When the Legends Die, typescript, undated (Box 17)
  - When the Legends Die, "miscellany" typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 17)
  - Redbook, correspondence with Hal and Barbara Borland and Willis Kingsley Wing, 1949-1960; 2 (Box 17)
  - Wing, Willis Kingsley, correspondence, 1947-1961; 3 (Box 17)
  - When the Legends Die, typescript carbon (in box labeled "And Then Came the Man"), undated (Box 17)
  - An American Year, reviews, comments and letters, circa 1946-1954; 3 (Box 18)
  - Wing, Willis Kingsley, correspondence, circa 1935-1943; 2 (Box 18)
  - High, Wide and Lonesome, comments in the New York Herald Tribune, 1956 December 2 (Box 18)
  - High, Wide and Lonesome, typescript notes for book, circa 1950 (Box 18)
  - High, Wide and Lonesome, reviews, circa 1955 (Box 18)
  - High, Wide and Lonesome, correspondence and typescripts, circa 1950 (Box 18)
  - High, Wide and Lonesome, printer's copy, typescript carbon, circa 1955 (Box 18)
  - The Greater Hunger, typescript with notes, undated (Box 18)
  - The Greater Hunger, printer's copy, typescript, 1962; 3 (Box 18)
  - The Amulet, scrapbook of notes and comments, 1957-1961 (Box 19)
  - The Amulet, printer's copy, typescript, 1957; 2 (Box 19)
  - The Youngest Shepherd, scrapbook of reviews and comments, 1962 (Box 19)
  - The Youngest Shepherd and The King of Squaw Mountain, typescripts, 1964 (Box 19)
  - "Dream of Glory," ( The Amulet ), typescript carbon, 1937 (Box 19)
  - Sundial of the Seasons, first yellow carbon, 1955; 2 (Box 19)
  - Sundial of the Seasons, text and illustration layouts, circa 1955
  - Beyond Your Doorstep, typescript carbon, 1961; 2 (Box 19)
  - Retire to What?, typescript carbon, circa 1948 (Box 19)
  - Retire to What?, correspondence, circa 1948 (Box 19)
  - "Great Westering," typescript, circa 1939 (Box 19)
  - "Countryman," essay, typescript carbon, circa 1954 (Box 19)
  - Countryman, first carbon, undated (Box 19)
  - Countryman, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 19)
  - Book of Days, notes, kills, etc., undated (Box 20)
  - Our Natural World, material for anthology, undated (Box 20)
  - "Non-Fiction, H.B., 1929---," scrapbook with articles and correspondence, 1929-1965 (Box 20)
  - "Non-Fiction Articles, H.B., 1937---," scrapbook with articles and correspondence, 1932-1962
  - "Magazine Fiction," scrapbook with short stories by Hal Borland and by Hal and Barbara Borland, 1925-1956 (Box 20)
  - Clippings and poem, draft, 1922-1968 (Box 21)
  - Our Natural World, charts, drafts and revisions, 1965 (Box 21)
  - The Last Gentleman, typescript, 1953 (Box 21)
  - And So We Were Married, typescript carbon, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Typescripts of unpublished short stories by Hal and Barbara Borland, 1948-1954; 2 (Box 21)
  - "The Intruders," typescript carbon, 1951 November 18 (Box 21)
  - "Cave in New Mexico," typescript, undated (Box 21)
  - "Spangles for a Dream," typescript carbon, 1950 February 14 (Box 21)
  - "The Man Who Forgot," typescript, 1954 (Box 21)
  - "The Glade," typescript and typescript carbon, 1950 March 24 (Box 21)
  - "The Moon and Mr. Rex," typescript and typescript carbon, 1948 (Box 21)
  - "Angeline," typescript carbon, 1948 (Box 21)
  - Prairie Harvest, typescript carbon, undated; 2 (Box 21)
  - Assorted magazines with writings of Hal Borland, 1964-1968; 3 (Box 21)
  - Penny, typescript and typescript carbon, undated; 2 (Box 22)
  - This World of Wonder, typescript, typescript carbon and typescript (photocopy), circa 1973; 3 (Box 22)
  - Borland Country, typescript and typescript carbon, undated; 2 (Box 22)
  - A Place to Begin: The New England Experience, typescript carbon, undated; 3 (Box 22)
  - Parents' Magazine Enterprises, Inc., correspondence and articles, 1971-1975 (Box 22)
  - Borland Country, typescript, 1971 (Box 23)
  - History of Wildlife in America, typescript carbon and correspondence, 1975; 2 (Box 23)
  - History of Wildlife in America, printed text and illustrations in binder labeled "Daily Journals", circa 1975 (Box 23)
  - History of Wildlife in America, correspondence, circa 1975 (Box 23)
  - Country Editor's Boy, typescript carbon, undated; 2 (Box 23)
  - Country Editor's Boy, typescript, 1975; 2 (Box 23)
  - Penny, typescript carbon, undated; 2 (Box 23)
  - This World of Wonder, typescript carbon, undated (Box 23)
  - Seasons [Sundial of the Seasons?], typescript carbon, undated (Box 23)
  - "Condors," typescript carbon, correspondence and printed version, 1974 (Box 23)
  - Printed excerpts from Beyond Your Doorstep and America Is Americans, undated (Box 24)
  - Hill Country Harvest, galley proof, 1967 (Box 24)
  - "I am an American," musical setting by Walter Sickles, 1942 (Box 24)
  - Countryman, typescript, 1965 (Box 24)
  - High, Wide and Lonesome, typescript carbon, 1956; 2 (Box 24)
  - Hill Country Harvest, typescript, undated; 3 (Box 24)
  - Sundial of the Seasons, typescript carbon working sheets, circa 1946; 2 (Box 24)
  - New York Times editorials, final copy and work sheets, 1965-1967; 2 (Box 24)
  - "America Is My Beat," study of Hal Borland by Kenneth R. Clark, 1954 (Box 24)
  - Hal Borland poems with music by Lee Erwin, sheet music and correspondence, 1962-1971 (Box 24)
  - Our Natural World, typescript, circa 1965; 9 (Box 25)
  - Our Natural World, galley proofs, 1965; 3 (Box 25)
  - The Flagler News, correspondence, clippings, photocopies and newspapers, 1965-1969; 2 (Box 26)
  - New York Times editorials, typescript and typescript carbon, 1968-1969; 2 (Box 26)
  - Untitled short story, typescript, undated (Box 26)
  - Country Editor's Boy, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 26)
  - Country Editor's Boy, notes and worksheets, typescript, circa 1966 (Box 26)
  - The Greater Hunger, typescript carbon, undated; 2 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence from New York Times readers, 1978-1980 (Box 27)
  - New York Times, correspondence and research for articles, 1962-1977 (Box 27)
  - The Quiet Comes, tape recording of Hal Borland editorial, 1975
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access to this material is restricted pending reformatting.
  - New York Times editorials, scrapbooks of clippings, 1941-1973; 9 (Box 27)
  - "Youth Novel," typescript, undated (Box 28)
  - "Forty-Eight States," typescript, 1946 (Box 28)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, correspondence and photocopies of permission forms from Reader's Digest, 1979-1980 (Box 28)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, reviews, circa 1979 (Box 28)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, correspondence, circa 1979; 2 (Box 28)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, galley proofs, 1979; 2 (Box 28)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, typescript photocopy, 1979; 3 (Box 28)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, copy editor's typescript, 1979; 3 (Box 28)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, page proofs, 1979 (Box 28)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, uncorrected proof, 1979 (Box 28)
  - The Coloradoan, University of Colorado yearbooks, 1919-1920; 2 (Box 29)
  - Progressive Magazine, scrapbook of columns, 1957-1977 (Box 29)
  - The Berkshire Eagle, scrapbooks of columns, 1958-1977; 8 (Box 29)
  - Borland family history, 1980 (Box 30)
  - This Hill, This Valley, illustrations by Peter Marks, circa 1957 (Box 30)
  - This Hill, This Valley, pre-publication letters sent out by Simon & Schuster, 1957 (Box 30)
  - Croy, Homer, correspondence, 1957-1963 (Box 30)
  - Permissions and related correspondence, 1952-1970 (Box 30)
  - Reynolds, George F., correspondence, 1947-1964 (Box 30)
  - Audubon Magazine, articles and correspondence, 1967-1980; 5 (Box 30)
  - J.B. Lippincott, correspondence, 1955-1967; 9 (Box 30)
  - High, Wide and Lonesome, script for television program, 1956 (Box 30)
  - Unsorted writings, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 30)
  - Poems, drafts, holograph and typescript, by Barbara Dodge Borland, undated (Box 31)
  - "Working with Hal," typescript carbon, by Barbara Dodge Borland, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Personal correspondence about Hal Borland, circa 1978 (Box 31)
  - Personal biographical material about Barbara Dodge Borland, 1922-1980 (Box 31)
  - Personal: St. Margaret's School about Barbara Dodge Borland, 1922-1980 (Box 31)
  - Barbara Dodge Borland correspondence, 1979-1980 (Box 31)
  - The Greater Hunger, correspondence and financial papers, 1962-1972; 2 (Box 31)
  - The Greater Hunger, reviews and autographing events, 1962-1972 (Box 32)
  - Walking With Hal, correspondence and clippings, by Barbara Dodge Borland, 1979-1980 (Box 32)
  - Printed material relating to Barbara Dodge Borland, undated (Box 32)
  - Clippings of writings by Hal Borland, 1964-1976 (Box 32)
  - Simon & Schuster, correspondence, 1957-1964 (Box 32)
  - Permissions and related correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 32)
  - Unidentified typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 32)
  - Author's Guild, correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 32)
  - New England Experience: A Place to Begin, typescript, 1980 (Box 33)
  - The Audubon Society, correspondence, 1963-1974 (Box 33)
  - Audubon Magazine, correspondence and writings, 1968-1970; 2 (Box 33)
  - Our Natural World, permissions and correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 33)
  - "Books: The Priceless Legacy," typescript carbon and correspondence, 1966 (Box 34)
  - "Life," typescript carbon and correspondence, undated (Box 34)
  - Twelve Moons of the Year, condensed version, 1979 (Box 34)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, bound galley, 1981 (Box 34)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, copyread typescript carbon, undated (Box 34)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, typescript, corrected, undated; 2 (Box 34)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, design copy, typescript (photocopy), 1981 (Box 34)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, galley proofs, 1981 (Box 34)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, master proof galleys, 1981 (Box 34)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, repro proofs, circa 1981
  - A Countryman's Flowers, layout, circa 1981
  - A Countryman's Flowers, research and correspondence, 1973, undated; 2 (Box 35)
  - A Countryman's Flowers, typescript carbon, undated; 2 (Box 35)
  - Countryman's Woodland, typescripts, articles and clippings, undated (Box 35)
  - Countryman's Woodland, typescript carbon, undated (Box 35)
  - Countryman's Woodland, typescript carbon, undated (Box 35)
  - Rocky Mountain Tipi Tales, unused sketches, circa 1926 (Box 35)
  - Poems A-S, typescript and typescript carbon, undated; 4 (Box 35)
  - Poems T-Z, typescript and typescript carbon, undated; 3 (Box 36)
  - Poems for Barbara, typescript and typescript carbon, undated (Box 36)
  - Poems for friends, typescript and typescript carbon, 1956-1976, undated (Box 36)
  - "About the artist [B.A. King]," typescript carbon, undated (Box 36)
  - "Stillmeadow Daybook, by Gladys Taber," review, typescript carbon, undated (Box 36)
  - Address concerning simplification of scientific language, typescript, 1971 December 27 (Box 36)
  - "By Bus to Peoria," typescript carbon, 1944 (Box 36)
  - Commencement speech given at Housatonic Valley Regional High School, typescript, undated (Box 36)
  - "Flagler: Home Town," typescript carbon, 1944 (Box 36)
  - Notes for a television debate with Morris Ernst, typescript, 1945 (Box 36)
  - Speech given at school, Stamford, Connecticut, [1950?] (Box 36)
  - "Speech given at Mesa Verde, Colorado to National Federation of Women's Clubs," typescript, undated (Box 36)
  - "For Barbara," poem and music, photocopy, undated (Box 36)
  - "In Memoriam," by Bernard Heiden, printed version with correspondence, 1964 (Box 36)
  - "Seasons," illustrations, undated (Box 36)
  - When the Legends Die, correspondence, photographs and notes about film, 1971-1973 (Box 36)
  - When the Legends Die, correspondence, 1964-1975 (Box 36)
  - Unidentified correspondence, 1935-1970 (Box 36)
  - "A" General, correspondence, 1938-1978 (Box 36)
  - A.S.P.C.A., correspondence, 1959 (Box 36)
  - Annenberg, Walter, correspondence, 1963 (Box 36)
  - Association of Interpretive Naturalists, correspondence, 1973 (Box 36)
  - Atkinson, Brooks, correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 36)
  - "B" General, correspondence, 1944-1980 (Box 36)
  - Baldwin, Faith, correspondence, 1956 (Box 36)
  - Beatty, C. Francis, correspondence, 1963-1975 (Box 36)
  - The Berkshire Eagle, correspondence, 1959-1968 (Box 36)
  - Berkshire-Litchfield Environmental Council, correspondence, 1963-1971 (Box 36)
  - "C" General, correspondence, 1948-1977 (Box 36)
  - Caras, Roger, correspondence, 1966-1976 (Box 36)
  - Cavey, Dr. J. E., correspondence, undated (Box 37)
  - Cobb, Boughton, correspondence, 1970 (Box 37)
  - "D" General, correspondence, 1944-1978 (Box 37)
  - Dempsey, Gov. John, correspondence, 1970 (Box 37)
  - DeVoto, Bernard, correspondence, [1933?] (Box 37)
  - "E" General, correspondence, 1942-1976 (Box 37)
  - Eiseley, Loren and Mabel, correspondence, 1964-1973 (Box 37)
  - "F" General, correspondence, 1935-1976 (Box 37)
  - Farb, Peter & Oriole, correspondence, 1964-1980 (Box 37)
  - "G" General, correspondence, 1921-1980 (Box 37)
  - Grasso, Gov. Ella, correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 37)
  - Griffin, Arthur, correspondence, 1962-1979 (Box 37)
  - "H" General, correspondence, 1956-1981 (Box 37)
  - Haas, Victor P., correspondence, 1963-1977 (Box 37)
  - Harper's Magazine, correspondence, 1973 (Box 37)
  - "I-J" General, correspondence, 1946-1980 (Box 37)
  - "K" General, correspondence, 1934-1981 (Box 37)
  - Kieran, John, correspondence, 1959-1977 (Box 37)
  - King, B. A., correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 37)
  - Knight, Eric, correspondence, 1938-1971 (Box 37)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., correspondence, 1962-1970 (Box 38)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood, correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 38)
  - "L" General, correspondence, 1941-1974 (Box 38)
  - Leighton, Claire, correspondence, 1972 (Box 38)
  - "M" General, correspondence, 1939-1981 (Box 38)
  - McCord, David, correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 38)
  - "N" General, correspondence, 1954-1979 (Box 38)
  - Natural History, correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 38)
  - The New York Times, correspondence, 1956-1972 (Box 38)
  - "O" General, correspondence, 1934-1978 (Box 38)
  - Ogburn, Charlton, correspondence, 1967-1980 (Box 38)
  - Osborn, Robert, correspondence, 1964-1976 (Box 38)
  - "P" General, correspondence, 1935-1978 (Box 38)
  - "Q" General, correspondence, 1970 (Box 38)
  - "R" General, correspondence, 1962-1980 (Box 38)
  - Ribicoff, Abraham, correspondence, 1972-1979 (Box 38)
  - Richter, Conrad, correspondence, 1968 (Box 38)
  - "S" General, correspondence, 1944-1980; 3 (Box 38)
  - "Sagendorph, Robert, correspondence, 1957-1973 (Box 38)
  - Sarton, May, correspondence, 1955-1970 (Box 38)
  - Saturday Review, correspondence, 1944-1948 (Box 38)
  - "T" General, correspondence, 1946-1980 (Box 38)
  - Taber, Gladys, correspondence, 1955-1980 (Box 39)
  - Teale, Edwin Way, correspondence, 1964-1972 (Box 39)
  - Templeton Secondary School, correspondence, 1979 (Box 39)
  - "U-V" General, correspondence, 1943-1981 (Box 39)
  - "W" General, correspondence, 1946-1973 (Box 39)
  - Weygant, Ida "sister Noemi," correspondence, 1964, undated (Box 39)
  - Wyeth, Andrew, correspondence, 1964 (Box 39)
  - "X-Z" General, correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 39)
  - Correspondence regarding speeches and lectures, 1955-1972 (Box 39)
  - Biographical material, 1962-1974, undated (Box 39)
  - Collection requests, 1957-1979 (Box 39)
  - Copyright assignments, New York Times, 1945-1972 (Box 39)
  - Inscriptions, 1962-1974, undated (Box 39)
  - Synopses of writings and financial summaries, undated (Box 39)
  - Book reviews by Hal Borland, clippings, 1970-1972 (Box 40)
  - Editorials and short articles by Hal Borland, clippings, undated (Box 40)
  - Obituaries and tributes, clippings, 1978 (Box 40)
  - An American Year, clippings, circa 1945 (Box 40)
  - Beyond Your Doorstep, clippings, 1962 (Box 40)
  - Country Editor's Boy and Countryman: A Summary of Belief, clippings, 1965, undated (Box 40)
  - Countryman's Flowers, reviews and book jacket, undated (Box 40)
  - Gentle Art of Walking and Golden Circle, ephemera, undated (Box 40)
  - High, Wide & Lonesome and Hill Country Harvest, clippings and ephemera, 1967, undated (Box 40)
  - History of Wildlife in America, clippings, 1976 (Box 40)
  - Homeland, clippings, 1969 (Box 40)
  - Old Farmers Almanac and Our Natural World, clippings, 1973, undated (Box 40)
  - Penny, clippings, 1972 (Box 40)
  - This Hill, This Valley, This World of Wonder, and Twelve Moons of the Year, clippings, 1957-1973, undated (Box 40)
  - When the Legends Die, clippings, 1963 (Box 40)
  - Clippings about friends and acquaintances, undated (Box 40)
  - General clippings and ephemera, undated (Box 40)
  - Unpublished Audubon book, binder of tear sheets, undated (Box 41)
  - Unpublished fiction about homesteading, typescript carbon, undated (Box 41)
  - Unpublished material and correspondence in binder, 1963-1965 (Box 41)
  - Teacher's calendar, 1976 (Box 41)
  - Unpublished material, typescript, undated (Box 41)
  - New York Times editorials, scrapbooks of clippings and typescript material, 1945-1976; 4 (Box 42)
  - Pittsburgh Press columns, scrapbooks of clippings, 1966-1978; 3 (Box 43)
  - The Dog Who Came to Stay, five-part serialization in Dutch magazine De Spiegel, printed version, 1965
  - Holiday magazines with writings of Hal Borland, 1978-1979
  - Boy's Life and American Education magazines with writings of Hal Borland, 1966, 1985
  - Newspapers with writings of Hal Borland, 1970s; Stored in: Oversize Box 57
  - Russian magazine containing "Life" by Hal Borland, 1976; Stored in: Oversize Box 57
  - Assorted printed versions of Hal and Barbara Borland writings, 1960s-1990s (Box 44)
- II. April 1991 Acquisition, 1904-1990; 5.25; (7 boxes)
  This group contains writings, correspondence, and personal papers of Barbara Dodge Borland, with some material related to Hal Borland.
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 117
  - Poems, drafts, holograph and typescript, undated; 11 (Box 45)
  - Diaries, 1984-1986; 10 (Box 46)
  - Magazines with Barbara Borland writings, 1980s-1990s (Box 47)
  - Unsorted correspondence, 1990 (Box 47)
  - Poems, drafts, holograph, undated (Box 47)
  - "Recipes Book," typescript, circa 1985 (Box 47)
  - "Gardening Book," typescript carbon, circa 1960 (Box 47)
  - "Cooking material," typescript, undated (Box 47)
  - Pictures and negatives for gardening book, circa 1960 (Box 47)
  - Columns on gardening for The Berkshire Eagle, clippings and typescript, undated (Box 47)
  - The Berkshire Eagle, correspondence, 1960 (Box 47)
  - Wing, Willis Kingsley, correspondence, 1960 (Box 47)
  - "Eyes, also doctors and dentists," correspondence and printed material, 1980s (Box 48)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 48)
  - Alfred A. Knopf, correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 49)
  - "Luv Story," draft dictated by Barbara Dodge Borland, 1984 (Box 49)
  - "Night Nurse," draft, undated (Box 49)
  - Flagler correspondence, 1978-1988 (Box 49)
  - "Christmas '85," correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 49)
  - National Audubon Society, correspondence and printed material, 1980s (Box 49)
  - Collin, Fran, correspondence, 1983-1990 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 49)
  - Photographs, 1904-1984; 2 (Box 49)
  - Correspondence and loose papers, undated (Box 49)
  - Magazines and tear sheets, 1950s
  - "Witches Laughter," typescript and correspondence, 1986, undated; 2 (Box 50)
  - Contracts and copyright for The Greater Hunger and "Garden Book", 1985-1987 (Box 50)
  - "Garden/Cookery Book," correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 50)
  - "Heigh-Ho the Merrio," typescripts, undated (Box 50)
  - "So You're Going to the Hospital," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 50)
  - Class and workshop material for future fiction book, drafts, holograph and typescript, undated; 2 (Box 50)
  - Unsorted writings, drafts, holograph and typescript, undated; 3 (Box 50)
  - Unsorted writings removed from unidentified black binder, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 50)
  - "Miscellaneous lines and ideas," drafts in black binder, undated (Box 50)
  - Unsorted writings, drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 50)
  - "Strange Music," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 50)
  - "Happy Birthday," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 50)
  - Unsorted writings, typescripts, undated (Box 50)
  - Red leather binder containing unsorted personal papers, correspondence, and typescripts, undated; 2 (Box 50)
  - This is the Way My Garden Grows, drafts, holograph and typescript and printed material, circa 1986; 2 (Box 51)
  - National Audubon Society, correspondence, 1983; 2 (Box 52)